<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tori Vaz</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 08:53:38 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 08:53:38 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adult-ing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s already been two years since I graduated, but my picture of where I would be today back in 2016 is pretty different than where I am now. I’m happy to report that I have, as of this week, finally accepted a full-time position as a web developer, but the milestone, while very exciting, is a little bittersweet when I think back to the big dreams when I finalized my exit from undergraduate life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was met with a competitive job market, and it was tough to push past the feelings of self-doubt that started to form after being left adrift interview after interview. Every time an opportunity arose, it felt like even if I put tons of effort into applications, phone calls, and interviews, I was left with not even so much as a response. When I did get a response, it was usually automated- “You didn’t make the cut for a real person to bother with spending time reviewing your resume.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of applications demand a tremendous amount of personal attention from the applicant, but the volume prohibits hiring managers from granting the same courtesy- I found myself half-heartedly clicking through application websites that sometimes barely even functioned. One company site deleted my entire application with an error message every time I got to the last page, which led me in a Sisyphusian loop several times before I finally ceded defeat. Whenever I got excited about an opportunity, it ended in disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected it for the first six months or so after I graduated, but after lenders of student loans started to send me bills every month, I started to feel a lot of pressure and despair. It felt like I would never be able to justify all the time I spent in college- I took restaurant jobs to pay the rent, which sapped my energy to pursue any career goals. I started to consider just going back to culinary school, since I knew I could cook and it was starting to feel like no one would give me a chance as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain didn’t help. With ADHD, there’s a trait called “rejection-sensitive dysphoria” (RSD)- an intense negative feedback response to being rejected from things. You get fixated on an idea, and when that thing doesn’t pan out because of what feels like a personal failing or mistake, you start to develop a really strong aversion to doing that thing anymore. For example, when I’m playing video games, if I fail a task, I might get this feeling so strongly I can’t continue. There are a lot of factors, but specific examples might be dying at a hard boss more than once- it feels like you’ve failed, and the RSD feeling can make it miserable to keep going. I ran into something similar with job applications- I would put in a lot of effort for applications, and when the effort was wasted or I was rejected, I just did not feel like doing that thing anymore and over time, I eventually stopped altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not a conscious thing, either- I told myself I would apply to some new jobs soon, I still combed job sites and even got interested in positions- but instead of applying, I would procrastinate or just talk myself out of it by reading the listings: “Well, I don’t have much experience in this skill they are looking for, I don’t want to waste my time with this job.” - a lot of thoughts like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These kinds of behaviors, as you might imagine, make job hunting extremely difficult. I had to work through a lot of these instincts my brain has to avoid wasted effort and rejection in order to be able to seek out jobs. In fact, the inciting action of me finding this job was actually me getting fired from my previous one. Without the shelter of barely making it paycheck to paycheck, I was forced to redouble my efforts to kickstart my sleeping career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I’ve been wondering what I could have done differently to get here to the starting line sooner, but…I really don’t know. I guess I would have sought out more job resources earlier, and maybe tried to push network connections harder than online applications- unless you are a super genius whose resume will float to the top algorithmically, I really &lt;em&gt;do not think you can find a programming job from an online application alone.&lt;/em&gt; Unless you have an in at the company, it really feels like these applications are largely filtered out and all positions are filled through network contacts. You’ll hear that over 70% of job openings are not posted online- do not scoff at that statistic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I’ve went through a lot of self-doubt to get here, and I’m sure there’s much more in my future, but I am going to try to remain excited about where I am and what I can accomplish here. Tori out! :sparkle:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 18:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/adulting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/adulting</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Oatmeal in a Jar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, I started a new job that requires me to make a nontrivial commute. I love it, but it can be hard to get going in the morning to make breakfast when I have a long drive every day. So, easy breakfast solutions became necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this breakfast because I can prepare it in advance and stash it in my purse or cupholder on my way to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oatmeal in a Jar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
1/3 cup instant oatmeal&lt;br /&gt;
1 tsp chia seeds&lt;br /&gt;
1 tbs flaxseed meal&lt;br /&gt;
1 tbs brown sugar&lt;br /&gt;
1 tbs nuts (I use sliced almonds)&lt;br /&gt;
1 tbs dried fruit (I use sweetened dried cranberries)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine in a 2-cup mason jar and top off with hot water when ready to eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try putting a can cozy around the jar if you want to keep it warm longer. Go ahead and play with the ingredient ratios to your taste! You can also add a little almond milk if you would like it to be creamier. Another really fruit/nut combo is chopped walnuts and dried apple pieces or bananas (I unfortunately have a banana allergy, but they pair excellently with oats, dried or fresh. If I could eat them they would definitely be a go-to.  :’(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your favorite easy breakfast tricks? :sparkle:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/oatmeal</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/oatmeal</guid>
        
        
        <category>recipe</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ooblets!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Games with a cutesy, earnest cartoon charm and soft, bright color palettes are among some of my favorites. Games like &lt;em&gt;Katamari Demacy&lt;/em&gt; and its successors, with their crisp lines and minimalist models, allow for some really clean looking techniques for displaying ridiculous amounts of chaos and clutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3581/3486753797_692d80bc86.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;forever&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think about what I love about the upcoming game &lt;em&gt;Ooblets&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Katamari&lt;/em&gt;’s art style comes to mind. being made by Rebecca Cordingley (&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/nonplayercat&quot;&gt;@nonplayercat&lt;/a&gt;) and Ben (&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/perplamps&quot;&gt;@perplamps&lt;/a&gt;). Self-described as a “Harvest Moon meets Pokémon meets Animal Crossing”, the player will be able to grow and raise adorable vegetable friends called Ooblets, hanging out on the farm and also meeting other farmers in battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ooblets.com/images/Metatag_image.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ooblets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m particularly excited to play the &lt;em&gt;Harvest Moon&lt;/em&gt;-esque farming aspect of the game. I’ve poured many long hours into &lt;em&gt;Harvest Moon&lt;/em&gt; (and more recently, &lt;em&gt;Stardew Valley&lt;/em&gt;), and so far the farms and crops look extremely cute. The fact I can customize my character, house and farm never hurts either. That by itself would have sold me on the game, but it’s just half the package here- you also get to raise dozens of tiny little creatures that follow you around like Pikmin. When is this game coming out again?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ooblets.com/images/all-crops-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;garden&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official answer is that it is slated sometime for 2018, but as a species we are completely unable to make trustworthy claims about game release dates. So, I imagine the real answer is closer to “whenever it’s finished”– though it seems as if the devs are very busy trying to stick to that deadline in this case. At any rate, I’m really excited to see the release! I would recommend following Rebecca on twitter, or checking out her awesome &lt;a href=&quot;http://patreon.com/nonplayercat&quot;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt;, where all kinds of cute updates get posted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ooblets.com/images/TSvuZip.gif&quot; alt=&quot;shrumbo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Shrumbo is my favorite lil boy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 06:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/ooblets</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/ooblets</guid>
        
        
        <category>games</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chana Masala</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If there’s a cookbook out there worth me gushing over here, it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leannebrown.com/&quot;&gt;Leanne Brown’s &lt;em&gt;Good and Cheap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a cookbook that prioritizes accessibility, variety and frugality in a way that a lot of cookbooks just can’t measure up to. A lot of “healthy college cookbooks” have cheap recipes, yes- but honestly, as someone who invested in several during her college years, none were very useful. Often the recipes were so simple it barely merited a page (fried egg on ramen, anybody?) and other recipes didn’t even work, especially baked goods. I imagine that these were barely tested. They didn’t inspire or challenge me in the way I am looking for. I hope those books served somebody well, but I wanted more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.leannebrown.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/xchana-masala-1024x680.jpeg.pagespeed.ic.CVkLxBeuL6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;masala&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipes in &lt;em&gt;Good and Cheap&lt;/em&gt; are infinitely riffable, a quality I deeply appreciate. When you get comfortable in the kitchen, you often read recipes more like outlines than specific directions; Brown offers creative substitutions and additions for every recipe, setting out to equip her readers with a variety of tools and techniques rather than offering rigid instructions to live by. And if you find that approach intimidating, the recipes themselves are written in clear language that avoids making assumptions about the cook’s experience, prioritizing accessibility and clarity for all skill levels. It’s a delicate balance, and I really admire the efforts made in this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many recipes are available on her website, including my new favorite go-to weeknight dinner &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leannebrown.com/chana-masala/&quot;&gt;Chana Masala&lt;/a&gt;. Easily thrown together with a can of tomatoes and some cooked chickpeas, it goes amazing with the raita yogurt sauce and handmade roti flatbreads that are also provided in the book. Spicy, warm, filling and- if you prep the chickpeas ahead of time or used canned- done in less than 30 minutes. That’s good enough for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has anyone else tried recipes from this book? It’s quickly becoming my bible for meal planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.leannebrown.com/wp-content/themes/openkitchen/images/xgood-and-cheap-sidebar-1x.jpg.pagespeed.ic.fyxqvr8mwd.webp&quot; alt=&quot;book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time,
Tori Vaz&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 06:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/chana-masala</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/chana-masala</guid>
        
        
        <category>recipe</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
